Ò×¿¼·¶ÎÄÒ»
In the above picture,
a collection of job-seekers with high academic degrees swarm to an employer,
only to be told that technicians alone are in demand.
What is reflected in the picture is an emerging phenomenon¡ªthe gap
between supply and demand of the job market.
A recent survey indicates that jobs such as service and sales account for
a percentage as large as 80%,
while young men show little interest in these ¡°blue-collar¡± occupations.
In contrast,
the majority of students strive to be engaged in ¡°white-collar¡± professions,
fields offering insufficient job opportunities.
At the same time, students are liable to insulate themselves from the society,
thus unable to put into practice what they have learned from the books.
As a result, when students graduate,
they get a diploma but little experience and capacity, which, however,
are valued by the employers.
In my view,
the solution relies largely on the joint efforts of school authorities and students themselves.
On the one hand, schools should provide guidance for students,
encouraging them to incorporate book learning into practical skills.
On the other hand,
it is advisable for students to come down to earth and accumulate experience
related to their future job. Only in this way,
can they better adapt to the society and find a suitable position in it.